Pimp Hello friends, welcome to another IPO video.
Today we are going to talk
about the IPO of Star Health Insurance Limited.
Should one invest in this IPO or not? If one should invest in it, then
how much should one invest?
How much of this IPO will remain in the grey market.
We will know all this in this video.
Watch this video completely so that you can understand well whether to
invest in this IPO or not.
First of all, let us know about the main gate
and when will this IPO come. The
main gate of this IPO is from 30th November to 2nd
December 2021 and its price is
870 rupees to 90 rupees and
its lot size of 16 shares is like a yagya.
Its trading in the grey market is around
20 to 40%. So if you were to compare these shares with
87000 rupees, then the market spread is
very low. The market spread is around three to four percent.
After this, let us talk about its listing
in Delhi in December and allotment will be done on
7th December. The issue size is 7219
points.  This issue is of Rs 18 crore, this
is a fresh issue of Rs 2000 crore and on 5249, when the issue price of Rs 18 crore is Rs 18 crore, then the investors are
reducing their stake. If you
place the offer at Rs 1609, then yours will be Rs 14400
and it will be listed on both NSE and BSE. A
quota of 10 percent has been kept for retail investors. After this, let us talk about
subscription. The current issue of the subject is
running at 0.12 multiple,
that is 12 per cent, it is currently subscribed. If we
talk about GPS on the first day, then its
negative IPS means its loss in this
GPS and its lagging behind is - in
62 and Network, this is, so
its 23 per cent is - in and Navy is
Rs 57 per share till 30th September 2021.
After this, now let us talk about its profit and loss.
Its profit in 2019 was Rs 128 crore.
Its profit in 2019 was Rs 268 crore.  It was and
in 2021, look at its arrangement of
825 Crore, in 2019 and 2020, the
company remained in profit in both the years and in 2021 the company has been
in loss, while there are a
lot of difficulties due to quality, so due to this it has had to
face class,
if we talk about payers, then look at Star,
which is behind - sectors and
ICICI Lombard has f5 in plus
and New India Assurance Company, which is a
government company, the P pro of Choice is
currently there, let's
talk about this
about the company, the company is in the Insurance Act
and in the Insurance Act they have many
varieties of health insurance
and 737 banks are now in 126 states and
four union territories, while in the third zone,
this company currently has
10,870 hospitals empanelled
in the health insurance sector and if we talk about the
promoters' holding, the holding of motors is
also 66 percent,
after the IPO it will come down to 58 percent.  This is your
motor and motor, see in this, the main Rakesh
Jhunjhunwala ji is its promoter,
today we talk about what is an IPO, the
main object of an IPO is the company, the
right to increase its capital, the main
capital has been shown a little and the anchor investors have
invested Rs 17 crore in Bigg Boss, anchor investors have invested Rs 13 crore in 3217,
you can read on the screen that
all this has been invested by the anchor investors, let's
talk about the disclaimer,
see, in this IPO there is very little in the grey market, so there will
not be much profit in it and the company will provide long-term protection,
for this you will see, there is a lot of competition in the insurance sector,
you also have many good companies, you can invest in it, there is
SBI Life or
ICICI Life, HDFC Life, there are
many companies which are performing well,
so you should
invest only after consulting your financial advisor,
we do not have any advice regarding the time in IPO,
this video has been made only for educational purposes,
friends,
videos related to mutual funds and share market are
on this channel  I keep uploading, so I request you to
subscribe to this channel so that
you keep getting information continuously.
You will keep getting updates on all the videos that are coming in the future. Thank
you very much for watching this video completely.